<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<theprintedstore>
<item category=" Tutorials / 3d Printing">
    <title partner="yes">Photogrammetry</title>
	<thumbnail>./images/blog/photogrammetry.jpg</thumbnail>
    <images>
	<img1 alt="photogrammetry">../images/blog/photogrammetry.jpg</img1>
	</images>
	<partner link="./blog/photogrammetry.php"></partner>
	<paragraphs>
	<p1>A funny sounding word, with a lot of meaning. It is, taking precise and exact measurements from photographs. 
		Typically methods like sonar, radar, and lidar are used with imagery analysis in a computational effort to produce 
		two dimensional and three dimensional depth fields based on the sensory input. There are multiple subcategories branching 
		off like stereophotogrammetry and stereoscopy. But if you look at them as a whole, and call it all photogrammetry. You are 
		left with the art of taking three dimensional scenes, stripping them of their depth, turning them into two dimensional scenes, 
		and then recalculating depth for scene reconstruction. And doing the process in reverse as well, allows you to decide if you want 
		photo realistic models in your games, or taking 3D game and movie scenes and tricking your brain into thinking it has depth. 
	</p1>
	<p2>Technology is getting more advanced and so is the software, it is now very simple to use almost any camera to take pictures 
		with no supplemental sensory input and process the photos into usable depth field data.
	</p2>
	<p3>Using real world scale can allow you to take accurate measurements of stockpile volume. Easily determine distances, routes, size, 
		height, and structural integrity with accurate colors and textures. This opens up a whole new world of surveying, but also for graphic 
		design as well.
	</p3>
	<p4>Being able to produce photo realistic video game art is a game changer, literally. The ability to scan yourself and your house into games 
		is in the near future. But for now, graphic designers are selling these photo realistic models on the open market, so you may have already played 
		a game using this technology. 
	</p4>
	<p5>But what is next? If photogrammetric technology keeps advancing, and it keeps getting easier to do. Then it will be easier to scan more things, 
		I think an exact virtual replica of the entire world, all of its cities, and all of its people could be 
		expected.
	</p5>
	</paragraphs>
	<external alt="Home">../index.php</external>
  </item>
<item category=" Tutorials / 3d Printing">
    <title partner="yes">3D Printing</title>
	<thumbnail>./images/blog/3DPrinting.jpg</thumbnail>
    <images>
	<img1 alt="3DPrinting">../images/blog/3DPrinting.jpg</img1>
	</images>
	<partner link="./blog/3DPrinting.php"></partner>
	<paragraphs>
	<p1>For years artisans and craftsman have found a home selling their goods on the handmade marketplace Etsy. 
	From knitted scarves, wood carved toys and customized jewelry, Etsy has precipitated a renaissance in handcrafted products. 
	New research from the Association For Creative Industries reports this creative economy has grown to a staggering $43.9 billion. 
	That’s a 45% increase from the $30.1 billion measured in 2011, making creativity one of the fastest growing markets of the decade. 
	</p1>
	<p2>The highly customized handicraft market isn’t restricted to traditional trades, however. With the emergence of desktop 3D printing, 
	non-conventional digital designers are creating an innovative niche of made-to-order 3D printed items. Unlike their analog counterparts, 
	digital artists only need to invest their time in the initial design, with the product then 3D printed ad-infinitum. The freedom from not 
	having to hand make the same design frees the designer to focus on the creative and business aspects of administering a successful store. 
	Without the limitations of human labor, a successful digital artist can far exceed the scale limitations of producing their products by hand.
	</p2>
	<p3>Despite the innovations in desktop fabrication, there are still several limiting factors preventing the widespread adoption of 3D printing 
	by designers and artists. The upfront cost of a 3D printer, while decreasing, is still significant. Creating printable files (called “slicing”) 
	also requires skill, patience and trial, and error. 3D printers are also notoriously maintenance prone, as well as slow. It’s not uncommon for 
	3D prints to take hours and even days. Without several printers running in parallel, it quickly becomes a challenge to keep up with demand.
	</p3>
	<p4>Fortunately, several online 3D print services have risen to the challenge. Companies like SpeedWright offer on-demand 3D printing, with a 
	wide selection of color and materials. Fast turn around, combined with drop shipping, allows a pay-as-you-go business model. Traditional 
	manufacturing requires expensive mold making and minimum order quantities in the thousands. By leveraging an online 3D printing service, 
	designers can quickly prototype, sell, and ship new products while getting validation in real time. 3D stores have uncapped growth potential 
	thanks to the scalability afforded by these services.
	</p4>
	<p5>It’s projected the 3D printing market will reach a $33.58 billion by 2022. Online 3D printing services allow effortless access to this 
	expanding market, which is outpacing traditional manufacturing year after year. Stores of the future will focus on content creation while 
	agile 3D printers will handle manufacturing, supply chain logistics, and delivery. Just-in-time manufacturing with deep customization will 
	remove the barriers of small business production, allowing unparalleled innovation. Anyone with an idea and a laptop can offer their product 
	to the masses, without the upfront costs and difficulty of dealing with overseas manufacturers.
	</p5>
	</paragraphs>
	<external alt="Home">../index.php</external>
  </item>
</theprintedstore>